(
"ai_sub_version": "1.11.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
3D新衣装お披露目日
白銀ノエル生誕祭 2025
睡夢 -suimu-
3D New Outfit Reveal Day
Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025
Suimu -suimu-
2025年11月24日(月/祝) 21:00～START
Nov 24, 2025 (Mon/Holiday) 21:00~ START
他にも初披露が…!?
And other first reveals...!?
SHIROGANE NOEL
NAKIRI AYAME
OOZORA SUBARU
USADA PEKORA
SHIRANUI FLARE
HOUSHOU MARINE
YUKIHANA LAMY
TSUNOMAKI WATAME
白銀ノエル生誕祭 2025
睡夢 -suimu-
Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025
Suimu -suimu-
快眠！安眠！スヤリスト生活
Refreshing Sleep! Deep Sleep! Syarist Life
目指せ快眠
Aim for refreshing sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win that deep sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams
理想の眠りを求めて
Searching for the ideal slumber
さあ 始めよう
Come on, let's begin
おやすみ
Goodnight
ノンレム 睡眠 レム 睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
私は囚われの姫
I'm a captive princess
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle
一人閉じ込められては
Trapped all alone
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
I just sleep every single day
今宵も布団に入り
Getting into bed again tonight
スヤスヤリスト生活
Live the "Zzz-Syarist" life
枕もシーツも
The pillows and the sheets...
硬くて眠れない
Are too hard, I can't sleep
（君も寝具にしてやろうか！）
(Shall I turn you into bedding too?!)
目指せ快眠
Aim for refreshing sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win that deep sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams
ふかふかの枕手に入れて
Getting my hands on a fluffy pillow
この疲れ癒したい
I want to heal this fatigue
恐れず前進
Move forward without fear
ほぐせよ全身
Relax your whole body
瞼を閉じたなら
Once you close your eyelids
スベスベのシーツの上で
Upon the smooth sheets
さあ 始めよう
Come on, let's begin
おやすみ
Goodnight
ノンレム 睡眠 レム 睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
私は囚われの姫
I'm a captive princess
悲鳴が響く夜に
In the night where screams echo
一人で檻を抜け出し
Escaping the cage alone
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
I'm heading out for a walk today too
幾多の試練を越えて
Overcoming many trials
新たな寝具を求めて
In search of new bedding
元
Once more
エマグマで
to the Emagma
猛毒で
with deadly poison
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if I die
（寝どこ 雲海にしてやろうか！）
(Should I turn your bed into a sea of clouds?!)
掴めよ快眠
Grasp that deep sleep
疲れて安眠
Restful sleep when tired
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, beyond the dreams
ハイテク目覚まし
High-tech alarm clock
手に入れて
I've got it in my hands
気持ちよく目覚めたい
I want to wake up feeling great
まだまだ前進
Moving forward still
華麗に変身
Transforming elegantly
ごはんを食べたなら
Once I've eaten my meal
魔法のベッドに
Onto the magical bed
ダイブして
Dive in
さあ
Now
始めよう
Let's begin
おやすみ
Good night
明日はもっと
Tomorrow will be
今日よりずっと
much better than today
いい夢見れるかな
I wonder if I'll have nice dreams
フワフワの羽根に包まれて
Enveloped in fluffy feathers
ココロゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content
目指せよ快眠
Aim for that deep sleep
勝ち取れ安眠
Win that restful sleep
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams
理想の眠りを
Seeking for
求めて
the ideal sleep
さあ
Now
始めよう
Let's begin
おやすみ
Good night
あと５分
5 more minutes
おやすみ
Good night
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
スヤァ
Zzz...
うーーー！
Ugh...!
はい、こんまっする！
ホロライブ３期生の白銀ノエルです！
Yes, Kon-massuru!
Shirogane Noel from Hololive 3rd Gen here!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my live today!
そしてハッシュタグはこちら！
And the hashtag is this one!
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025、たくさんスクショして
SNSに投稿してください！
#白銀ノエル生誕祭2025. Please take lots of
screenshots and post them on social media!
今日のえーライブのテーマなんですが、
見ての通りね、睡眠安眠癒やしライブとなっております
The theme of today's live is, as you can see, a
'Sleep, Restful, Healing Live'.
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくので、
ぜひ皆様も盛り上がってください！
It's going to get even more exciting towards the second half,
so please enjoy it everyone!
てな感じで、１曲目はえー
「快眠！安眠！スヤリスト生活」を歌わせていただきました
So, the first song was
'Kaimin! Anmin! Syuairist Seikatsu'.
あの曲中のね、あの団長踊りながら
ま、変身したシーンがありましたけど
There was a scene where Danchou transformed
while dancing during the song.
わかった？わかったっていうか、みんな気づいてる？
Did you realize? I mean, did everyone notice?
てか、おメイクがちょっと変わりました！
My makeup has changed a bit!
お気づきでしょうか。ま、具体的にね、
どういうところが変わったかと言いますと
I wonder if you noticed. Well, specifically,
what has changed...
あの髪の毛がですね、あのサラサラによりなりました！
My hair has become even more silky!
ええ、サラサラになって、特に後ろとかね、
わかるかな。ほら、サラサラー
Yes, it's so silky. Especially from the back,
can you tell? Look, silky!
もう本当にいつでもあのシャンプーのＣＭ待ってます
Seriously, I'm waiting for a shampoo commercial anytime now.
てな感じで、サラサラになったのと、
あとおメイクもね、ちょっと変わっております
So, besides my hair being silky,
my makeup has also changed a bit.
ま、いろんな表情ができるようになったんですけど
I can now make various expressions.
えーと、なんかえ、なんか代三、
ノイちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってるって、お、おん
Wait, Daisa said something that would
make Noel-chan angry...
え、なに、おい。ちょっと太った？
んんん！なになに！
What? Did you get a bit fat?
Hmph! What?!
太ってないよ、最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん
I'm not fat! I've been working hard on my diet lately!
てな感じで、前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど、
マイルド怒りになりました。はい
Before, I'd get really seriously angry,
but now it's a 'mild' anger. See?
という感じで、あのちょっとね、いろんな表情ができるようになったんで
それも踏まえて、あのライブ見てくれると嬉しいです
So, I can make various expressions now. Keeping that in mind,
I'd be happy if you enjoyed the live.
そして、ま、ノイちゃんも変わったんですけど、
この変わったね、あのお姿でさらに
And besides me changing, with this new look, the stage today is...
本日のステージはこちらです！
like this!
えーすごいね、全景。わあーー！
Wow, look at the full view! Whoa!
なんか本当癒やしって感じだよね。もう本当に綺麗に。
It really feels like 'healing', doesn't it? It's so beautiful.
はい、作っていただきました。ま、ここのね周り、
そう、周りねこれ雲。雲の海みたいな感じで
They made it so beautifully. And this area...
this is a sea of clouds.
プカプカってなっています。ええ。
It's all fluffy and floating. Yes!
そしてね、ま、こうやって雲の海から上もね、
すごーい、綺麗！
And above this sea of clouds,
the ceiling is also amazing! So beautiful!
なんか飾りがぐるぐるぐるーっと回っておりますので
The decorations are spinning around.
いやなんかね、あのこれからちょっとゲストパートとかもあるんですけど、
なんかそれに合わせていろいろと変わっていくみたいなので
Well, we have the guest part coming up next,
and it seems like things will change even more for that,
ぜひ楽しみにしてみてください！
so please look forward to it!
それでは次の曲、レッツゴー！
Alright then, let's go to the next song!
僕は今夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey
僕は今
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey
あの星の
To that star's
島まででも　飛んでゆける
island, I can fly
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
Singing a palm-sized song, my dream-eater
君のそばにも　辿り着ける
I can reach your side too
ユメクイ
作詞・作曲：愛
Yumekui (Dream Eater)
Lyrics & Composition: Ai
最初に描いた
The dream I first drew...
夢を思い出せなくなって
...I can no longer remember
遊びを　大人になったから？
Is it because I became an adult about playing?
右か左かへ　いつまでも迷って
Wandering between right and left forever
太陽が反転するまで　しゃべりこんだ
We talked until the sun flipped over
一つだけ　ポケットに入れてきたもの
The one thing I put in my pocket
真っ赤な　この愛を持って
Is this deep red love I carry
僕は今
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey
あの星の
To that star's
島まででも　飛んでゆける
island, I can fly
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
Singing a palm-sized song, my dream-eater
君のそばにも　辿り着ける
I can reach your side too
カラフルなもやに　心を奪われ
Stolen away by a colorful haze
ちょっとしたことに　つまづいた
I stumbled over some small things
擦りむいたところに　君がくれたのは
On the place I grazed, what you gave me was
恥ずかしいくらいの　可愛らしい絆創膏
A cute bandage that was almost embarrassing
叶えるたびに
Every time I make it come true
食いつくすユメクイ
The dream-eater devours it
叶えるたびに
Every time I make it come true
また夢を見る
I dream once again
いくつになっても
No matter how old I get
僕は今
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey
寄り道して
Taking a detour
プレゼントを見つける
I find a present
手のりうたうたう
Singing a palm-sized song
僕のユメクイ
My dream-eater
描いた未来に
In the future I drew
君がいつもいる
You are always there
僕は今
I am now
夢旅の中
in the middle of a dream journey
あの星の
To that star's
島まででも　飛んでゆける
island, I can fly
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
Singing a palm-sized song, my dream-eater
君のそばにも　辿り着ける
I can reach your side too
君のそばで
By your side
ずっと夢を見る
I will dream forever
半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Incredible, papparappappappapparappa
限界突破っぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, papparappappappapparappa
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Every day is incredible, papparappappappapparappa
限界突破っぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, papparappappappapparappa
明日の私に幸あれ
May happiness come to the me of tomorrow
最敵温度　塞ぎ切るゴースト
Optimum temperature, a blocking ghost
八百万の穏やかな的外要素
Eight million gentle, off-target elements
何の気ないと　超あっけらかん
Innocently, super nonchalant
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの誰かにバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye to that someone who's getting in the way without malice
自分時間　堕落タイム確保　5時～9時は死守しますと
Securing my own time for depravity, I'll defend 5 to 9 at all costs
さらに甘い恋や甘い夢を忘れずに　とどのつまり
And not forgetting sweet love and sweet dreams, in the end
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm also issuing a warning that overwork is strictly prohibited
ねぇ楽して　上手くして　生きてくってもどかしいな
Hey, trying to live an easy and successful life is so frustrating
だって安定裏技一回きり　甘い蜜に罠がある　イェイ！
Because stable cheats are one-time only, there's a trap in the sweet nectar. Yay!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Play because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
Isn't it okay to cry when sad?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of the me of tomorrow, I'll somehow do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best so that I don't have to do my best tomorrow
総括じゃないやこれ多分そうだ　ないやいやることやってます
It's not a summary, yeah this is probably it, I'm doing what I need to do
What's & Bad 誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
What's & Bad, I don't care if nobody knows
私には私のマイルール　明日楽するためにはハイチーズ
I have my own rules, say 'cheese' to make tomorrow easy
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある毎日を生きたいのです
Surprisingly, I want to live every day with love and peace like this
Don't be shy 　ドキドキしたい　ドキドキしたい
Don't be shy, I want to feel excited, I want to feel excited
Let me shine 明日天気に慣れ
Let me shine, hope it's sunny tomorrow
To be excite 心もっと踊りたい
To be excited, I want my heart to dance more
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday 木金土日　イェイ！
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thu-Fri-Sat-Sun Yay!
辛くなったら歌う
Sing when it gets hard
むかついたら愚痴る
Grumble when annoyed
やりたいようにやる
Do as I want
それができたら苦労しないわ
If I could do that, I wouldn't be struggling
常に一喜一憂　してりゃ何でありゃと思たんから
Always fluctuating between joy and sorrow, thinking 'what was that' about everything
適度にセーブしディスは回避してまぁ頑張るのさ
Save moderately, avoid disses, and well, do my best
適当にまでは言わないがまぁ頑張るのさ
I won't go as far as saying 'carelessly', but well, I'll do my best
夢の中ではずっとぐうたらしてやるんだ
In my dreams, I'm going to be lazy all the time
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく明日の私のため Fight!
Not for someone else, but for the me of tomorrow, Fight!
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだから Fight!
Because I'll overcome even painful things just to make it easy later, Fight!
やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ Fight!
Do the things you don't want to do so you don't have to do the things you don't want to do, Fight!
あれ？これって結局頑張れてる私とっても偉いじゃないか Fight!
Huh? Doesn't this mean I'm actually doing my best? Aren't I great? Fight!
自分時間　堕落タイム確保　5時～9時は死守しますと
Securing my own time for depravity, I'll defend 5 to 9 at all costs
さらに甘い恋や甘い夢を忘れずに　とどのつまり
And not forgetting sweet love and sweet dreams, in the end
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよって注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm also issuing a warning that overwork is strictly prohibited
ねぇ楽して　上手くして　生きてくってもどかしいな
Hey, trying to live an easy and successful life is so frustrating
だって安定裏技一回きり　甘い蜜に罠がある　イェイ！
Because stable cheats are one-time only, there's a trap in the sweet nectar. Yay!
眠くなったら寝る
Sleep when sleepy
お昼過ぎに起きる
Wake up after noon
遊びたくて遊ぶ
Play because I want to play
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
Eat when hungry
嬉しかったら笑う
Laugh when happy
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
Isn't it okay to cry when sad?
明日の私のために今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of the me of tomorrow, I'll somehow do my best today
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best so that I don't have to do my best tomorrow
半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Incredible, papparappappappapparappa
限界突破っぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, papparappappappapparappa
毎日半端ないぱっぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Every day is incredible, papparappappappapparappa
限界突破っぱらっぱっぱっぱっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, papparappappappapparappa
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Kick the live booking and invent
そんな発明王に俺はなる
I'm going to be such an Invention King
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Kick the live booking and invent
そんな発明王に俺はなる
I'm going to be such an Invention King
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison self-esteem
自尊心
Self-esteem
歌うエジソン自尊心
Singing Edison self-esteem
自尊心
Self-esteem
幼少期の頃から家で聴いてた音楽はハウスミュージック
The music I've been listening to at home since I was a child is House music
サブスクのプレイリスト聞いて曲ディグったならクラブでDJ
If I dig songs from subscription playlists, I'll be a DJ at a club
パソコン開いたならDTM ソフトはAbleton Live
If I open a PC, it's DTM; the software is Ableton Live
だげど今
But right now,
作りたいのは
what I want to make
蓄音機
is a gramophone
サークルでの
At my club's
宴会芸
party trick
ノリで始めた
I started in the heat of the moment
バンドで
with a band
まぐれでバズって
We got lucky and went viral
メジャーデビュー
and made our major debut
なぜか今ではしがない
For some reason, now I'm just a lowly
ミュージシャン
musician
踊るエジソン
Dancing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
歌うエジソン
Singing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
踊るエジソン
Dancing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
歌うエジソン
Singing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
YouTubeを見て得る
Gained from watching YouTube,
1%のひらめき
1% inspiration
インスピレーション
Inspiration
SNS通して繋がる
Connecting through SNS,
発明家のコミュニケーション
inventor's communication
インスタ映え狙った投稿
A post aiming for the "Insta-look",
webニュースで情報収集
gathering info from web news
間違いなくこれから
Without a doubt, from now on
時代来るのは活動写真
it's the era of motion pictures
いや、絶対来ると思うんだけどな〜
No, I definitely think it's coming though...
踊る暇があったら
If you have time to dance,
発明して
then invent
歌う暇があったら
If you have time to sing,
発明して
then invent
ライブのブッキング蹴って
Decline the live show bookings
発明して
and invent
そんな発明王に
I will become
オレはなる
such an inventor king
踊るエジソン
Dancing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
歌うエジソン
Singing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
踊るエジソン
Dancing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
歌うエジソン
Singing Edison,
自尊心
self-esteem
今日はこのまま
Today, just as it is,
さよならじゃないよ。
it's not "goodbye".
手をとってくれたなら！
If you'd only take my hand!
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
On a night when even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ。
I'll take you with me.
それは、例えば遠く離れていたって
Even if, for example, we were far apart,
手をつないでいられるような奇跡のような
like a miracle that lets us keep holding hands,
話をしよう
let's talk of such things.
窓は開けておいて。
Leave the window open.
今日までを思い出して
Thinking back on everything up until today,
一つずつ並べたら
if I lined them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして
I'd start worrying about tomorrow's rain,
どうも眠れないみたいだ。
it seems I just can't sleep.
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change,
変わらなきゃいけないことも
and things that must change,
少し忘れたまま
leaving them behind for a bit,
窓の外眺めていたんだ。
I was gazing out the window.
雨が降り出すその前に
Before the rain starts to fall,
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I could make it to where you are,
目を閉じでみたんだ。
so I tried closing my eyes.
そしてこのまま遠くへと行こう！
And like this, let's go far away!
手をとってくれるかな。
Will you take my hand?
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
A night when even secrets fall asleep,
君と泳いでいくよ。
I'll go swimming through it with you.
街の明かりが消える度に笑って
Laughing every time the city lights go out,
路地裏で抱き合おう
let's embrace in a back alley,
馬鹿みたいな話をしよう！
let's talk about silly things!
窓は開けておいて。
Leave the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや
Precious things,
無くせないものを
and things I can't lose,
教えてくれたのは今日みたいな
it was nights like tonight
夜を重ねて折り上げてきた私たちに響く音。
that taught them to me, a sound echoing within us, woven from all those nights.
夜が来るたびに心が躍ってしまうのは
The reason my heart leaps every time night comes
また一つ重なっていく
is because one more thing is being added...
...また一つ重なっていくから
...because they'll stack up once more.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜 私たちだけで眠ろう
Tonight, let's sleep just the two of us.
誰にも言わないで
Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に
Just before you fall asleep...
名前を呼んで
...call out my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My heart aches with wishes that won't come true,
俯いてしまうけど
and I end up looking down...
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから
...but I'll go invite you to a town where no one else is.
今日はこのままサヨナラじゃないよ
Today isn't goodbye just like this.
手をとってくれたなら
If you'd take my hand,
秘密も眠りに付くような夜に
on a night when even secrets seem to fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you away.
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
Even if, for example, we were far apart,
手を繋いでいられるような
as if we could keep holding hands...
奇跡のような話をしよう
...let's talk about something like a miracle.
窓は開けておいて 聞こえる？
Keep the window open. Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや
The precious things,
無くせないものを教えてくれたのは
and the things that can't be lost...
今日みたいな夜を重ねて
The one who taught me was...
織り上げてきた私たちに響く音
...the sound echoing for us, woven together through nights like today.
響く言葉
Echoing words.
はい！ということで皆様！
Alright! So everyone!
今回のライブ、なんと新衣装がっ！
In this live, surprisingly, there's a new outfit!
ありましたー！
Ta-da!
ということで、あの、びっくりしたかな？
So, um, were you surprised?
びっくりしたんじゃないかなと思います！
I think you might have been surprised!
こちらね、すごい、あの、
This one is very, um,
煌びやかな衣装となっているんですけど
it's quite a gorgeous outfit,
ちょっと今、スクショタイム撮る？
Wanna take some screenshots now?
イェーイ！
Yay!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
ぜひあの、ハッシュタグでね、
Please, using the hashtag,
ぜひ呟いてください。
please tweet about it.
可愛いでしょ？
It's cute, right?
何やらね、この後ちょっと衣装のいろいろ
Apparently, later on, about the outfit details...
細部までちょっと見る機会がありそうな
I feel like there might be a chance to see the details,
予感がするので、
so for now,
一旦スクショだけお願いします！
just some screenshots, please!
そして、あとこちらね、見て！
And also, look at this!
手首にプラプラって紐があるんだけど
There are these dangling strings on the wrists,
これね、取れます！
but these can be removed!
じゃ、取ってもらおうかな？
So, shall I have them taken off?
えいっ！えいっ！
Ei! Ei!
ということで、はい、取れまーす。
And so, yes, they come off.
こちらバージョンもスクショ撮ってもらおう。
Let's have some screenshots of this version too.
ヘイ！
Hey!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
ぴゃ〜！
Pya~!
ね、すごい可愛らしい衣装。
Right? A very lovely outfit.
ちょっとね、あの、ドキドキするんですが、
I'm a bit, um, nervous, but...
うん。
Yeah.
いや〜、なんか、でもちょっと一人寂しいな。
Man... but it feels a bit lonely all by myself.
なんか、ダインさん...
I wonder, Dain-san...
あ！いた可愛い！
Ah! There he is, cute!
ね、なんか、モゾモゾしてる。
Look, he's squirming around.
お、どうしたどうした？
Oh, what's wrong?
うわぁ〜！
Uwaa~!
ダインさん飛んできた！
Dain-san flew over!
そんなにノエちゃんに会いたかったんかな？
Did you want to see Noe-chan that much?
可愛いね〜。
So cute.
いっぱいスクショ撮れた？
Did you get lots of screenshots?
ダインさんとのツーショット！
A two-shot with Dain-san!
可愛い。え？何々？
Cute. Eh? What is it?
あ、今日は安眠テーマで、あ、心地がいい。
Ah, with today's sleep theme, it's comfortable.
あ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
ん？曲のリクエスト？
Hm? A song request?
あ、子守唄みたいな曲が聴きたい。
Ah, you want to hear a lullaby-like song.
あ、そうなの？ダインさん。
Oh, really? Dain-san.
じゃあせっかくね、ダインさん来てくれたし、
Well, since Dain-san came all this way,
一緒に、じゃ、子守唄...
let's sing a lullaby together...
うん。歌うよ！歌う。
Yeah. I'll sing! I will.
だからちょっとついてきて。
So come with me for a bit.
一緒に行くよ。
Let's go together.
ほら、おいで！
Come on, over here!
ぼうやの夢よ
Little boy's dream...
小さな人の子よ
O little child of man,
森へ迷い込んだ
who wandered into the forest.
大きな...
A big...
空の羽が
The wings of the sky...
ぼうやは見えないのね
...you cannot see them, can you, little one?
何も知らないまるいほっぺよ
Round cheeks that know nothing of the world.
眠れや眠れ
Sleep, oh sleep,
静かな水辺においで
Come to the quiet water's edge.
ぼうやの夢は
The little one's dreams...
竜の背に運ばれて
...are carried on the back of a dragon...
山の向こうへ消える
...and vanish beyond the mountains.
よろずの子も並んで眠る
All the children of the world sleep side by side.
七つ数えたら
Once you count to seven,
仲よく眠って来る
everyone will fall into a peaceful slumber.
何も見えない
Seeing nothing,
小さなおめめよ
those tiny little eyes.
眠れや眠れ
Sleep, oh sleep,
そよぐ草むらにおいで
Come to the swaying grass fields.
ぼうやの夢は
The little one's dreams...
母さんを探しては
...search for their mother...
空の向こうへ帰る
...and return to the far side of the sky.
竜の背に運ばれて
Carried on the back of a dragon,
山の向こうへ消える
they vanish beyond the mountains.
プラネタリウム
作詞・作曲：愛
Planetarium
Lyrics & Composition: Ai
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく
The evening moon peeks out, as they fade away—
子供の声
the voices of children.
遠く遠く
Far, far away,
この空のどこかに 君はいるんだろう
somewhere in this sky, you must be there.
夏の終わりに二人で 抜け出したこの公園で
In this park we snuck out to together at summer's end,
あの星座 何だか 覚えてる
I somehow remember that constellation.
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see the same happiness.
あの香りと共に 花火がパッと開く
Along with that scent, fireworks suddenly bloom.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are.
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to run to you right now.
真っ暗で 何も見えない
In the pitch black where nothing can be seen,
怖くても 大丈夫
it's okay even if it's scary.
数えきれない星空が
The countless stars in the night sky...
今もずっと ここにあるんだよ
...are still here, and always will be.
泣かないよ
I won't cry.
泣かないよ　届くだろう　きれいな空だったから
I won't cry; they'll surely reach you, since the sky was so beautiful.
あの道まで響く靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of footsteps echoing to that road lingers in my ears.
大きな自分の影を見つめて思うのでしょう
Gazing at my long shadow, I find myself lost in thought.
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに　せつない気持ちふくらんでく
Though nothing should have changed, this painful feeling just keeps growing.
どんなに想ったって君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you're no longer here.
行きたいよ　君のそばに　小さくても　小さくても
I want to go to your side, even if I'm small, even if I'm small.
1番に　君が好きだよ　強くいられる
I love you more than anyone; you're the reason I can be strong.
願いを　流れ星に　そっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried softly whispering my wish to a shooting star, but...
泣かないよ　届くだろう　きれいな空に
I won't cry; they'll surely reach you, in the beautiful sky.
会えなくても記憶をたどって　同じ幸せを見たいんだ
Even if we can't meet, I'll trace my memories; I want to see that same happiness.
あの香りと共に花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks suddenly burst open.
行きたいよ　君のところへ　小さな手をにぎりしめて
I want to go to where you are, squeezing your small hand tight.
泣きたいよ　それはそれはきれいな空だった
I want to cry; it was such a very, very beautiful sky.
願いを　流れ星に　そっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried softly whispering my wish to a shooting star, but...
泣きたいよ　届かない想いをこの空に...
I want to cry; sending these unreachable feelings into this sky...
もう何十回もう何百回も　震むソラ見上げて
Dozens, hundreds of times, looking up at the blurred sky.
辿り着いた場所が　運命のダイヤモンド
The place I finally reached is the diamond of fate.
何千回もう何万回も　涙流したきみへ
To you, who has shed tears thousands, tens of thousands of times.
ねえ諦められたことはあったっけ？
Hey, was there ever anything you truly gave up on?
「憧れ＝限界」だから　もういらないよ
Because 'Admiration = Limit,' I don't need it anymore.
そこに留まるなんて　もったいないでしょ
Just staying there would be such a waste, wouldn't it?
それぞれの物語　交差する瞬間を
The moments where our individual stories intersect.
見つめる意味は
The meaning of gazing upon them is...
放った夢だけ　大きな弧を描いて
Only the dreams we released draw a great arc.
はちきれそうな煌めきを　消えることなく　どこまででも
A brilliance about to burst, never fading, going anywhere and everywhere.
世界の向こうに 届けよう
Let's send it to the other side of the world
終わることのない この胸の衝動は
This never-ending impulse in my heart
どうしたって どうしても
No matter what, no matter how
ぼくを呼んでいた
It was calling out to me
だから その先へと
So, towards what lies ahead
走り続ける
I'll keep on running
次へ 次へ
To the next, and the next
妄想だった 中途半端な
It was a delusion, a half-baked
不甲斐なさ抱えて 立ち尽くしていた
Helplessness that left me standing still
通り雨はプレリュード
The passing rain is a prelude
何千回も 何万回も
Thousands, tens of thousands of times
挑み続けた君へ
To you who kept on trying
ねぇ聴かせてよ「夢は叶うんだ」って
Hey, let me hear you say "dreams do come true"
『諦め＝完敗』ならば 絶対にないよ
If "giving up = total defeat," then that's definitely not it
だれに邪魔されようと ためらわないで
No matter who gets in your way, don't hesitate
託された情熱を
The passion I was entrusted with
落とさずにつないでいく
I'll pass it on without letting it go
そう 最後まで
Yes, until the very end
フラッグに誓い 勇ましく旗めいて
Swearing on the flag, fluttering bravely
鳴り止まないファンファーレ
The never-ending fanfare
いつも心に 流れていた
Was always flowing in my heart
遠い未来へ 祈るよう
Like a prayer towards the distant future
忘れられない あの日々の後悔を
The regrets of those unforgettable days
追いかけて 追いかけて 滑り込んだ この想い
Chasing it, chasing it, these feelings I slid into
青いソラに ふと溢れていった
Suddenly overflowed into the blue sky
遠く 遠く
Far, far away
トレビアンナイト
Trēs Bien Knight
終わらない 終わらない
Won't end, won't end
仕事が山積み終わらない
The pile of work just won't end
止まらない 止まらない
Won't stop, won't stop
それでも時間は止まらない
Even so, time won't stop
YO! YO! ヘトヘト たまり溜まったヘイト
YO! YO! I'm exhausted, the accumulated hate
連発お門違いバット コンボ メイス 銀座バット
Endless misplaced bats, combos, maces, Ginza bats
Swing 今日も一杯 今日も一杯
Swing, another full day, another full day
Found NO MORE 鞭 GIVE ME GIVE ME 汁
Found, NO MORE whip, GIVE ME GIVE ME juice
I see 奔走 ANYTIME 奔走 ANYTIME
I see, struggling ANYTIME, struggling ANYTIME
はぁ〜 溜め息ブレンドで エナジー空っぽだ
Sigh... an energy blend that's completely empty
自分自身に厳しすぎちゃう
Being too hard on myself
すぐさまヘラヘラ優等生 さっぱり足りない 順応性
Instantly a silly honor student, lacking any adaptability
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing myself properly
一番必要なものは
The thing I need most is
トレビアン ご褒美 頂戴
Trēs Bien, give me a reward
てんてこ舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say goodbye to the frantic rhythm
ドレミファの音にご覧
Look at the Do-Re-Mi notes
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰め込んじゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Don't cram it all in, getting more and more freedom
Uh
オーライ オーライ
Alright Alright
好きなもの食べ放題 オキシトシン増す脳内
All-you-can-eat favorite foods, oxytocin increasing in the brain
ほら もっともっとちょうだい 膨大
Look, give me more and more, massive amounts
Get Ready 多忙です たまに空振り
Get Ready, I'm busy, occasionally striking out
満ちた日こそ胸張り 大盛り
On days when I'm full, puff out my chest, extra serving
いらない まやかしの甘い夜更かし
Don't need fake sweet late nights
ハッピーになるため歌おう 声高らかに
Let's sing to be happy, loud and clear
自分自身がやっぱり一番
I am, after all, the number one
理性と欲望が平行線 望みは幸せエンドレス
Reason and desire are parallel lines, wishing for endless happiness
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing myself properly
我慢は身体に毒だよ
Endurance is poison for the body
トレビアン ご褒美 頂戴
Trēs Bien, give me a reward
てんてこ舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say goodbye to the frantic rhythm
ドレミファの音にご覧
Look at the Do-Re-Mi notes
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰め込んじゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Don't cram it all in, getting more and more freedom
窮屈な靴に疲弊 ストレス
Exhausted by tight shoes and stress
状態異常警戒から解放して
Release me from the status ailment alert
もっともっともっともっとまだまだ足りない
More, more, more, more, it's still not enough
本日は欲望解放パーティーナイト
Tonight is a desire-releasing party night
乾杯！
Cheers!
トレビアン　御褒美頂戴
Très bien, give me a reward
てんてこ舞いなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say bye-bye to this hectic rhythm
トレヴィ　驚異御礼
Très vie, thanks for the wonders
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰め込んじゃえ　どんどんフリーダム
Cram it all in, more and more freedom
ぎゅうぎゅうと夢の御褒美　どんどん好きになる
Packed with dreamy rewards, I'm liking it more and more
ビバ！
Viva!
輝夜の城で踊りたい
I want to dance in Kaguya's Castle
ハッハ！
Ha-ha!
おいで！おいで！誘惑のDance again
Come on! Come on! Temptation's Dance again
おいで！おいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on! Come on! To Kaguya's Castle
出逢いがあやつるミステリー
A mystery controlled by our meeting
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona
踊ろう！踊ろう！終わらないDance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! An endless Dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! In Kaguya's Castle
夜空を切りとるレーザービーム
Laser beams cutting through the night sky
私を見てよ
Look at me
まばゆい星が照らす想い
Feelings illuminated by dazzling stars
今宵の夢よ永遠に
May tonight's dream last forever
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow
ニパ！
Nipa!
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of the red rose
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently whisked away
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly
意味ありげに目をそらす
Averting my eyes suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon
触れた手がまだ熱い
Your touch is still burning
のがさずに抱きしめて
Hold me tight and don't let go
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
We call this miracle love, don't we?
おいで！おいで！情熱でDance again
Come on! Come on! Passionate Dance again
おいで！おいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on! Come on! To Kaguya's Castle
迷いを飲みこむエナジー
Energy that swallows hesitation
眠らぬパッショネイト
A sleepless passionate one
踊ろう！踊ろう！止まらないDance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! An unstoppable Dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! In Kaguya's Castle
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
A discotheque woven by the constellations
私も混ぜて？
Let me join in too?
きらめく星に誓う心
A heart swearing to the twinkling stars
儚い夢でいいわ
A fleeting dream is fine
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow the winds of tomorrow will blow
ラヨネ！
Layone!
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of the black rose
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be intensely whisked away
だから微笑んで
So please smile
追いかけてと目が誘う
My eyes invite you to chase me
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You are also the knight of the black moon
瞳の奥は熱い
The depths of your eyes are burning
つかまえて抱きしめて
Catch me and hold me tight
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
This miracle invites love, doesn't it?
Flare: 一緒に行こう。ついてきて。
Flare: Let's go together. Follow me.
Marine: 他の人を見ちゃ嫌。私だけを見て。
Marine: Don't look at other people. Look only at me.
Pekora: 後悔するわよ。楽しもう。
Pekora: You'll regret it. Let's have fun.
Noel: 早くしなさいよ。鈍いのですね。いいの。
Noel: Hurry up. You're slow, aren't you? It's fine.
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of the red rose
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently whisked away
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly
意味ありげに目をそらす
Averting my eyes suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon
触れた手がまだ熱い
Your touch is still burning
のがさずに抱きしめて
Hold me tight and don't let go
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
We call this miracle love, don't we?
はーい！
Haaay!
ということで、3期生のみんなと「輝夜の城で踊りたい」を歌って踊りました！
So, I sang and danced to "Kaguya no Shiro de Odoritai" with all the 3rd generation members!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ノエちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Noe-chan, happy birthday!
おめでとう！ ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Thank you!
ちょっと可愛いんじゃない？
Aren't you looking a bit cute?
はい、可愛い？
Yes, am I cute?
なんか服装に対して...
Like, compared to the outfit...
動きがちょっとね、あちゃちゃちゃと可愛く。
The movement is a bit, you know, cute and goofy.
可愛いですか？
Am I cute?
可愛い！
Cute!
すごいね、なんかここが。
It's amazing, like, right here...
ね、重... ここ大丈夫ですか？
Right, it looks heav... is this area okay?
おっぱいがお尻だよ、ノエちゃん。
Your boobs are like a butt, Noe-chan.
おっぱいがお尻だよ。
Your boobs look like butt cheeks.
今日からはさ、こう話せばいいのかな？
From today, maybe I should talk like this?
違う違う！ やだやだ！
No, no! Don't do that!
そんなことないなら。
If that's not the case...
えっと、今回の衣装はね、あの200万人の記念で、はい、作っていただきました。
Um, this outfit, well, it was made to commemorate reaching 2 million subscribers.
他にも変わったところ、今日のライブからであるんだけども...
There are other changes, starting from today's live performance...
ノエちゃん、どこがわかったの？
Noe-chan, what did we notice?
あれ？ マリンが怒ってる？
Wait? Is Marine angry?
メイク変えた。
I changed my makeup.
あ！ きゃー！
Ah! Kyaa!
え、気づいた？ ということで。
Oh, you noticed? So...
当たり前だろう。
Of course I did.
そうなんですよ。ちょっとメイク変わりました。え、大丈夫？
That's right. My makeup changed a bit. Is it okay?
全然違うじゃん！ 可愛い！
It's totally different! So cute!
ちなみに、お気に入りの顔がありましてね、ちょっとね、あの、お困り顔、お困り顔がね...
By the way, I have a favorite expression... a slightly, um, troubled face...
そう、可愛いでしょ？
Isn't it cute?
お口がね、ちょっとぷりっとなっておるんです。
My mouth is a little pouty.
あ、本当だ、ぷりって！ こだわりの！
Oh, it really is! So pouty! Nice detail!
食べちゃうぞ！ うわー！
I'm gonna eat you! Rawr!
うわーじゃなかった。え、じゃあちょっと衣装せっかくなんで...
That wasn't a 'rawr'. Well, since we have the outfit...
下からちょっと舐めるように、いきましょうよ。
Let's do a slow pan from the bottom up.
お靴から見ましょう、お靴から。
Let's start with the shoes.
おら、可愛いお靴！
Wow, what cute shoes!
いいでしょ？ ちょっとよく見せて。あ、ヒールなのです。
Nice, right? Let's get a good look. Oh, they have heels.
可愛い！
Cute!
普段はね、通常でぺったんこだから、ちょっと身長盛りました。
Usually I wear flats, so I've added some height.
リボン二個側、後ろにね！
Two ribbons on the side, at the back!
え、可愛い！ いいね、いいね。
Oh, cute! Nice, nice.
はい、じゃあちょっと舐めるように...
Okay, panning up slowly...
うわー！ いったいどんなおパンツ...
Whoa! I wonder what kind of panties...
マリーン、変態！
Marine, you pervert!
好奇心が。
Just curious.
こんな感じで、え、ちょっとそんなささっと終わんないで、まだ舐めてる最中...
Like this... hey, don't end it so quickly, it's still panning...
あー！
Aaaaah!
はい、ここね！ あの「L」がいてね、ノエルじゃなくて...
Yes, here! There's an 'L' here, it's not 'Noel' but...
ノエちゃん、ここ！ 皆さんご覧ください！ ここの、この、この胸の、この...
Noe-chan, here! Everyone, please look! This, this, this gap here in the chest area...
ここ、この、隙間、隙間、隙間！
Here, this gap, the gap, the gap!
わかります？ この乳と乳の間のこの隙間！
Do you see? This gap between her breasts!
本当だ、すごいね！
It's true, amazing!
隙間がね、ほら！
The gap, look!
うわー！
Whoa!
大丈夫ペコか？
Are you okay, Pekoka?
最高の衣装です。
It's the best outfit ever.
じゃあちょっと上見せるに当たって、このヒラヒラ取れるから、ちょっと取ってもいい？
Now for the upper part, these frills can come off, so can I take them off?
可愛い！ 見たい！ 取ってみて！
Cute! I want to see! Take them off!
取ってください！ はい！
Please take them off! There!
おー！ スッキリ！ 見やすい！
Ohhh! It's so much cleaner! Easier to see!
万歳！ 万歳！
Banzai! Banzai!
横はどうなってるのかしら？ ゆっくりクルクル回って。
I wonder what it looks like from the side? Spin around slowly.
クルクルクル...
Spinning, spinning...
あ、可愛い！ 髪の毛フワフワで可愛い！
Ah, cute! Your hair is so fluffy and cute!
髪型めっちゃ可愛い！ お姫様！
The hairstyle is super cute! Like a princess!
なんかリボンがこう髪に巻き込んである感じで。
The ribbons are woven into her hair.
そうなんよ、編み込んで。エッチョーも言ってましたけど、姫騎士なんで、お姫様も...
That's right, woven in. Like Ecchou said, I'm a princess knight, so I'm also a princess...
なってます！
I've become one!
可愛すぎる。こんなの好きになっちゃう。ちょっと解毒したいから、いつもの動きして。
Too cute. I'm falling for you. I need an antidote, so do your usual movement.
（動きを待つ）
(Waiting for the movement)
あ、なんか好きじゃなくなった。危ない、恋するところだった。
Ah, I don't like you anymore. That was close, I almost fell in love.
いやでも本当に可愛い衣装。本当におめでとう。
No, but seriously, it's a cute outfit. Congratulations.
ありがとう！ 衣装もマジで超可愛い。
Thank you! The outfit is really super cute.
いやでもさ、皆さん、今回は団長の衣装、新衣装お披露目だったから...
But everyone, this was for my new outfit reveal...
みんなにはちょっとアイドル衣装だったんですけど...
So everyone else was in their idol outfits, but...
みんなもさ、衣装持ってるじゃん。
You all have outfits too.
あ、そうよね！ 並んだりとかも今後したいな。
Oh, right! I want us to stand together in them in the future.
絶対しよう！ 並ぼう、並ぼう！
Let's definitely do it! We'll line up together!
てか、3期生でまた歌って踊りたいな！
Actually, I want us to sing and dance together as 3rd Gen again!
え、ちょっとそれ！ 踊りたい！ 絶対また一緒に！
Oh, yes! I want to dance! Definitely together again!
はい！ ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます！
Yes! So, from here, I have many important announcements to make!
まず、ホロライブ3期生の単独ライブ...
First, the Hololive 3rd Generation solo live concert...
「hololive 3rd Generation Live きらるん大作戦 最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ」開催決定しております！
"hololive 3rd Generation Live: Kirurun Operation - Ultimate Idols, You've Gotta Support Us!" has been confirmed!
イエーイ！ 待ってた、待ってた！
Yay! We've been waiting for this!
はい、日時ですが、2026年1月の17日と18日の2日間にわたって開催されます。
Yes, as for the dates, it will be held over two days, January 17th and 18th, 2026.
イエーイ！
Yay!
会場はね、あのデッカイ、そう、Kアリーナ横浜となってます。
The venue is that huge one, yes, K-Arena Yokohama.
昨日ね、なんと、まあちょっと二次先行がちょうど終わったことなんですけど...
Actually, the second pre-order lottery just ended yesterday, but...
なんかね、このあと、まあ先着の一般販売が12月の14日とかの...
Well, after this, general first-come-first-served sales will start around December 14th...
お昼の12時に...
At 12:00 PM...
まだまだね
It's still
きらめき、勝ち獲るチャンスあると思うので
the chance to win the sparkle, I think,
ぜひぜひ、勝ち獲ってください！
so please, do your best to win it!
お願いします！
Please!
そして配信チケットはね、まだありますので
And streaming tickets are still available,
絶賛発売中ですので、よろしくお願いいたします！
they're on sale now, so thank you very much!
お願いします！
We're counting on you!
そして、まあ、このライブを見てくださった方で「あー、買い忘れてる！」人はいないと思うけど
Also, well, I don't think anyone watching this live is thinking "Oh, I forgot to buy it!"
グッズの先行販売と受注販売も、明日の11月25日の18時までとなっております
But the early and pre-order sales for goods end tomorrow, November 25th, at 18:00.
明日ね！
Tomorrow, right!
そう、だからライブ会場でペンライト振りたいとか
Right, so if you want to wave a penlight at the venue,
配信見ながらペンライト振りたいよっていう人はぜひ
or if you want to wave one while watching the stream,
この機会をお見逃しなく！
don't miss this opportunity!
現地行く人はぜひとも絶対絶対持ってたほうが
People going to the venue should definitely, definitely have them,
盛り上がりますよ！
it makes it more exciting!
お願いします！
Please!
いやー、楽しみだね！
Man, I'm looking forward to it!
めっちゃ楽しみ！
So excited!
団長もね、ちょっとおメイク変えたから
I changed my makeup a bit too,
食べてるのも楽しみ！
so I'm looking forward to the feast too!
そんな感じで、せっかく来てくれたから意気込みを一言ちょっと言っておこうかなって
On that note, since you're all here, why don't you each give a quick shout-out?
一言ね、言っておこうかなって
Just a quick word.
誰から行くの？
Who's going first?
やる気満々だぜ！
I'm all fired up!
じゃあちょっとマリンからこういう順番で行きますか？
Well then, shall we go in this order starting with Marine?
マリン、すごい良いこと言ってくれるんだろうな
I'm sure Marine is going to say something great.
頑張るぞー！
Let's do our best!
楽しむぞー！
Let's have fun!
みんなで盛り上げるぞー！
Let's get everyone pumped up!
ありがとう！え、え、何？あ、あ、ああ…
Thank you! Wait, what? Oh, oh, wow...
光の速さで去っていった…
They left at the speed of light...
みんなありがとう！
Thanks everyone!
てな感じで、ここからはノエルちゃんの告知に行きます！
So, from here, let's move on to Noel's announcements!
まず一つ目はこちら！
First up is this!
白銀ノエル 誕生記念 2025
Shirogane Noel Birthday Memorial 2025
はい、今年も出ます。白銀ノエル誕生記念2025のグッズ、わーい！
Yes, they're coming out this year too. Shirogane Noel Birthday Memorial 2025 goods, yay!
生誕グッズ、まずはこちら！
For the birthday goods, first is this!
睡夢の世界へ！キラキラLEDアートパネル
To the World of Dreams! Sparkling LED Art Panel
イラストはMyungYi先生が描いてくれました。ありがとうございます、いつもお世話になってます。らぶちらぶち
The illustration was drawn by MyungYi-sensei. Thank you, I'm always in your debt. Love ya!
今回の生誕ライブのステージと新衣装がテーマになっております
The theme is the stage and new outfit from this birthday live.
LEDということで、こちら光るということでね、ぜひお部屋に飾って、今回のライブを思い出して、思い出にしてください
Since it's LED, it glows. Please display it in your room and remember this live performance.
はい、そして次はこちら！
Alright, and next is this!
色んなノエルちゃん♪ランダムマルチバンド
Various Noels♪ Random Multi-Band
まえり先生が描いてくれました。ありがとうございます。いや、色んなノエルちゃんがいますので
Drawn by Maerei-sensei. Thank you very much. There are various Noels here.
どのノエルちゃんがおうちに来るかなって楽しみにしつつ、届いたらマルチバンド、こちらお片付けの必需品となってます
Look forward to seeing which Noel comes to your home. These multi-bands are essential for organizing.
ノエルちゃんも使っておりますので、ぜひね、コードまとめる時とか、実用性に富んでますので使ってみてください
I use them too. They're very practical for things like organizing cords, so please give them a try.
次は、こちら！
Next is this!
姫騎士ノエル ぬいぐるみキーホルダー
Princess Knight Noel Plushie Keychain
昨年はサンタさんのノエルちゃんがぬいぐるみとしてキーホルダーで出たんですが、今回はせっかく新衣装が出たので
Last year we had a Santa Noel plushie keychain, but since I have a new outfit this time...
こちらでぬいぐるみキーホルダーを作りました。姫騎士として団員さんを守りますので、ぜひ肌身離さず持っててください
...we made a plushie keychain of it. I'll protect you as a Princess Knight, so please keep it with you always.
次は、こちら！
Next is this!
わんちょむ2wayネックピロー
Wanchom 2-way Neck Pillow
安眠に最適なネックピローなんですけど、今回はなんと、ひっくり返すとわんちょむになっているということで
It's a neck pillow perfect for a good night's sleep, but if you flip it inside out, it turns into Wanchom!
わんちょむは今年から団長のおうちにお迎えしたワンちゃんのことなんですけど、グッズにしちゃいました。ちょっとノエルちゃんの愛が入ってます
Wanchom is the puppy I welcomed into my home this year, and I've turned him into merchandise. It's filled with my love.
ぜひ団員さんのおうちにも迎えてください。最後にフルセットを見てみましょう。こちら！
Please welcome him into your homes too. Finally, let's look at the full set. Here it is!
誕生記念フルセット
Birthday Memorial Full Set
はい、今年もいっぱいグッズが出ました。ぜひぜひゲットしてみてね
Yes, we have lots of goods again this year. Please be sure to get yours.
そしてこの全部のフルセット特典があります。それはこちら！
And there's a bonus for buying the full set. Here it is!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
フルセットを購入してくださった方にチェキ風ブロマイドカード付いてきます。とても素敵！
Those who purchase the full set will receive a polaroid-style bromide card. It's wonderful!
イラストはMyungYi先生のイラストで、こちらに通常バージョンは箔押しの複製サインがぺたってなるんですけど
It features MyungYi-sensei's illustration. The standard version comes with a foil-stamped replica signature,
数量限定バージョンは団長の直筆サインが付いてきます。心を込めて書きますので、ぜひゲットしてみて下さい
but the limited quantity version comes with my actual handwritten signature. I'll sign them with all my heart, so please try to get one.
さらに、フルセットを購入してくれた方全員に特典ボイスも付いてきちゃいます。フルセット欲しいって皆思ったんじゃないでしょうか。ぜひゲットしてみて下さい
Furthermore, everyone who buys the full set will also get a bonus voice. I bet you all want the full set now, don't you? Please go and get it!
心を込めて撮ります。よろしくお願いします。
I'll take the photos with all my heart. Please look forward to it.
生誕グッズは22時カートオープンです。
Birthday goods cart opens at 22:00.
皆さん、ぜひゲットしてください！お願いします。
Everyone, please get them! Thank you.
さらに、さらに、重大告知があります。
And, and, there's a major announcement.
なんと、それは...
And that is...
はい！新曲があります！
Yes! There's a new song!
その新曲を発表するにあたって、なんと...
To announce the new song, well...
ちょっと今回スペシャルな方からコメントいただいてるみたいなんだけど...
It seems we have a comment from a very special person this time...
誰なんだろう？ノエルもわかんないな。誰でしょうか？
Who could it be? Noel doesn't even know. Who is it?
こんまっする〜！
Konmassuru~!
え、ちょっと待って！
Wait, what!?
白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shirogane Noel-san, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
そして、団員の皆さん、配信を楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？
And to all the knights, are you enjoying the stream?
楽しんでますか？
Are you enjoying it?
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。
I'm Kiichiro Sato, Governor of Oita Prefecture.
大分県広報広聴課、めじろんです！
I'm Mejiro-n from the Oita PR and Hearings Division!
なに！？ちっちぇ！
What!? So small!
この度は新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。
Congratulations on the announcement of your new song.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
今回、私がノエルさんの新曲のタイトル発表を任せていただけることになりました。
I've been entrusted with announcing the title of Noel-san's new song.
いいんですか！？
Is that okay!?
それでは早速曲名を発表したいと思います。
Now, I'd like to announce the song title right away.
お願いします！
Please do!
その名も...
The name is...
VAVAVA! バーチャル大分
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita
バーチャル大分！わーい！
Virtual Oita! Yay!
そうですね、バーチャル大分と入っていますので、大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな。
Well, since it's titled 'Virtual Oita', I suppose it's a song where you can enjoy Oita virtually.
はい！そうです！
Yes! That's right!
はい、大分のオススメたくさんありますよ！
Yes, there are many recommendations for Oita!
まずは何と言っても温泉です！
First of all, it's the onsen!
温泉！最高ですね！
Onsen! The best!
大分県は源泉数、湧出量ともに全国一位ですから。
Oita Prefecture is number one in Japan for both sources and volume.
一位です！
Number one!
他にも、関アジや関サバ、かぼすブリ、おおいた和牛、唐揚げなんかの食の魅力も満載ですね。
There's also plenty of food appeal, like Seki-aji, Seki-saba, Kabosu-buri, Oita Wagyu, and Karaage.
最高です！
The best!
ぜひ皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです！
I'd love for everyone to taste them!
はい！
Yes!
ノエルさん！大分を代表して応援しちょんけん！
Noel-san! I'm supporting you on behalf of Oita!
これからも大分県のPRを頼むけんな！
I'm counting on you to keep promoting Oita Prefecture!
えー！ありがとうございます！
Oh! Thank you!
新曲、しんけん楽しみしちょんけん！
I'm really looking forward to the new song!
それでは、おつまーする〜！
So, Otsumassuru~!
おつまーする！
Otsumassuru!
あ、めじろんも！おつまーする、おつまーする！
Oh, Mejiro-n too! Otsumassuru, Otsumassuru!
ということで、まさかの意外や意外、大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎さんに、新曲のタイトル発表と応援のコメントをいただきました。
So, surprisingly, we received the song title and words of support from Governor Kiichiro Sato of Oita Prefecture.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
あの、これ本当にノエちゃんびっくりで、本当にこれサプライズなんですけど。
Um, Noel was really surprised, this was a total surprise.
いや、本当にありがとうございました。まさかこんな日が来るなんて。
Thank you so much. I never thought this day would come.
いや本当にすごい方から応援していただいて嬉しいですね。
I'm so happy to be supported by such an amazing person.
団長最初何が起こったのかわからず、しかもめじろんも横にいて。
At first I didn't know what was happening, and Mejiro-n was there too.
あの、緑の。そう、いましたね。すごい可愛かったなと思います。
That green one. Yeah, she was there. She was very cute.
本当、ずっと団長大分育ちで、大分の魅力をバーっと配信で個人的に言ってるだけなんですけど。
Really, I've lived in Oita my whole life, and I've just been personally talking about Oita's charm on my streams.
いや本当日頃大分の魅力を伝えてきてよかったなと思います。
I'm really glad I've been sharing the charm of Oita every day.
もちろんこれからも個人的に、特に何か大きなことがあるわけではなく、個人的に団長大分の魅力を伝えていきたいなと思いますので。
Of course, I want to continue personally sharing Oita's charm, not because of anything big, but just personally.
皆さんもまだ大分に行ったことない人は、ぜひ大分行ってみてください！
For those who haven't been to Oita yet, please go visit!
いいところだよ！
It's a great place!
はい、ということで、新曲歌っちゃいたいと思います。
Alright, so I'd like to sing the new song.
聞いてください。
Please listen.
VAVAVA! バーチャル大分
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita
説明しよう、バーチャル大分とは、バーチャル九州の北東部に位置する、広大な大地。
Let me explain. Virtual Oita is a vast territory located in the northeastern part of Virtual Kyushu.
現実の大分県に限りなく近い地上の楽園。人はその地を、バーチャル大分と呼ぶ。
A paradise on earth very close to real-life Oita. People call that place, Virtual Oita.
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Releasing Virtual Oita to the world
バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Boiling the water in Virtual Oita
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running through Virtual Oita with you
バーチャル大分 おおいたどーん！
Virtual Oita, Oita-doon!
おおいたどーん！
Oita-doon!
君は降り立つ 魅惑の地獄の入り口
You land at the entrance of the enchanting Hell
絶えず湯沸く 誘惑の地
Enchanting land, always boiling water
海 かまど 白池 血の池
Umi, Kamado, Shiraike, Chinoike
鬼石坊主 鬼山 竜巻 バーン！
Onishi-bozu, Oniyama, Tatsumaki, Ba-an!
とり天 とりめし やせうま だんご汁
Toriten, Torimeshi, Yaseuma, Dango-jiru
中津からあげ 冷麺 関アジ 関サバ
Nakatsu Karaage, Reimen, Seki-aji, Seki-saba
かぼす あつめし まだまだ入るよ
Kabosu, Atsumeshi, more can fit
鉄の胃袋 大魔神
Iron stomach, Great Demon God
行こうぜ 久住高原 湯煙の温泉
Let's go to Kuju Highlands, steamy onsen
高崎山に 金鱗湖
At Takasakiyama and Lake Kinrin
青の洞門 由布川峡谷
Ao no Doumon, Yufugawa Gorge
進め 稲積水中鍾乳洞
Forward to Inazumi Underwater Stalactite Cave
果てしなき旅 一人遠足
An endless journey, a solo excursion
たどり着く先 食べる弁当
Reaching the destination, eating lunch
時空を超えた奇跡の大地
A miraculous land beyond time and space
バーチャル大分 行くぞー！
Virtual Oita, let's go!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, unleashing it on the world
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, boiling the water
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you
バババ バーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, unleashing it on the world
バババ バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, eating it all up
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you
バババ バーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
大分どーん！
Oita boom!
よだきい しゃあしい えらしい
Tiresome, noisy, and cute
しんけん やおね ふうがわり
Very much so, isn't it? Eccentric
なしか むげね せせろしい
Why? Pitiable and restless
だけど あんた 今 なにしちょん
But what are you doing now?
説明しよう バーチャル大分観光大使とは
Let me explain: A Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador
バーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち
is someone with a deep love for Virtual Oita
その魅力を余すところなく伝え続ける存在
who continues to spread its charm completely.
人は その大使の名を
People call such an ambassador
バーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ
a Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A
Virtual O-O-I-T-A
I wanna be 団長 団長 観光大使
I wanna be Danchou, Danchou, Tourism Ambassador
バーチャル O-O-I-T-A
Virtual O-O-I-T-A
団長 団長 観光大使 (自称)
Danchou, Danchou, Tourism Ambassador (Self-proclaimed)
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, unleashing it on the world
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, boiling the water
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you
バババ バーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, unleashing it on the world
バババ バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, eating it all up
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you
バババ バーチャル大分 大分どーん！
Ba-ba-ba Virtual Oita, Oita boom!
大分どーん！
Oita boom!
新曲MV公開、この後すぐ！
New music video release, right after this!
団員さん！
Order members!
今年もお誕生日をお祝いしてくれて 本当にありがとう〜♡♡
Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday again this year~ ♡♡
新衣装&新曲など...どうだったかな？！
How was the new outfit & new song...?!
少しでも好き〜ってなってもらえたら ノエちゃんとっても嬉しいです✨
I'd be so happy if you liked them even a little bit ✨
来年も一緒に同じ時間を 過ごせますように...🍀
I hope we can spend the same time together next year too... 🍀
大好きだよ〜〜♪
I love you~~ ♪